Roger Brown

Sr. Program Manager - DHL Global Forwarding

Vancouver, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Roger-Brown/633ce346b5a72436

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Many years experience in a leadership position in Information Technology (IT) including large-scale, complex systems along with a demonstrated track record of increasing levels of responsibilities. Well-rounded IT background including experience in implementing and coordinating IT Infrastructure across multiple timezones. Financial experience in Forecasting, Budgeting, Costing and Value Measurement as related to the IT environment. Exceptional management and communication skills. Focused on project management, priority setting, team development and motivation, contract negotiation and vendor relationships. A track record of fostering a team environment, managing customer expectations, and clean communications with other divisions and senior management.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- = Problem-Solver = Self-Disciplined = Visionary Leadership
- = Deadline-Driven = Continuous Improvement = Quality-Minded
- = Effective under Pressure = Persuasive Communicator = Determined
- = MS Office Expert = MS Project Expert = MS SharePoint Expert
- = BA Math & German = Masters in Business Admin = PMP 2002

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Project Manager

Washington State Department of Health - Tumwater, WA -

April 2016 to August 2016

(Temporary Assignment) Financial Systems Migration. Migrate the applications and reports used by the DOH Finance Group from a 2003 SQL Server environment to a 2012 SQL Server environment. This included migrating or recreating more than 100 critical daily, monthly and annual Financial Reports.

IT Project Manager

DHL Global Forwarding - Tempe, AZ -

April 2004 to July 2015

MGMS Airfreight System. Manage the roll-out of the Multiple Gateway Management System (MGMS) at the largest and busiest Import and Export Gateways in the DHL Global Forwarding (DGF) Air Freight network. This Program typically has no fewer than 100 distinct Projects in the Program Portfolio at any point in time. This is a Multi-Million Dollar Program.

IT Project Manager

American Express - Phoenix, AZ -

2002 to 2004

Managed the project to architect, consolidate and migrate a 10 Tb Sybase IQ Data Warehouse over to state-ofthe art Sun F15K servers with more than 100 CPUs and a total capacity of 300 Tb SAN attached storage. The migration included the consolidation of four database schemas into one unified model. This Data Warehouse services hundreds of internal users world-wide and provides hundreds of millions of dollars in fraud protection to American Express on an annual basis

IT Project Manager

SUMCO - Phoenix, AZ -

December 1995 to February 2002

Managed this Multi-Million Dollar IT budget across four US Divisions and directed the implementation of all the systems used by the various Administrative groups at this semiconductor facility. Facilitated standardization and consolidation of the JDEdwards Systems and Technology across all U.S. divisions. Hired and managed technical staff and project managers implementing and supporting the Administrative applications. Directed Operations, including NT/Desktop support, Unix System Administration and Oracle Database Administration. Hardware Platforms and Databases included HP-Oracle, AS/400-DB2, RS/6000-

DB2 and NT-SQL/Server and the Wide Area Network and corporate firewall consisting of Cisco hardware. 1 recommendation available upon request

EDUCATION

MBA in Business & Economics

Washington State University - Vancouver, WA

Bachelor's in Education, Majors: Mathematics & German

Concordia University - Seward, NE

SKILLS

MS Office Expert, MS Project Expert, MS SharePoint Expert (10+ years)

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rambyte

AWARDS

Fulbright Scholarship

Studies in German Culture, History and Literature Conducted at Goethe Institutes in Nürnberg, Göttingen and Berlin, Germany

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Project Management Professional (PMP)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Contributor: FISH of Cowlitz County http://FishOfCowlitzCounty.org/